#### **RESUME**

#### Nitin Namdeo Pawar

<u>nitinpawar1702@gmail.com</u> Mob.9168452069,7776909215

# Career Objective

Obtaining a challenging position in a high quality engineering environment where my technical knowledge and academic skills will add value to organizational operations.

# Patent

Sr.	Patent/Applic	Title	Date of
no.	ation Number		published
01	44/2021	A Friction-Based Analysis of Heat Transfer Efficacy on Fluted Tubes on a Diesel Engine Cylinder	29/10/2021
02	387415-001	Solar Powered Device to Track Nutrients in Agricultural Water	31/05/2023
03	388431-001	Development and Analysis of Led Bulb with Different Array of Fins by a Passive Mode of the Cooling System	16/06/2023
04	405202-001	IOT based smart vehicle black box with security system	20/01/2024

#### Awards

Sr. no.	Title				
01	As the NSS Programme officer at Mumbai University, I worked on blood collection during the COVID-19 pandemic at the 7th best college.				
02	Awarded 'Vidyasagar Award' in 12th International Conference on 'Computing, Communication, and Sensor Networks,' CCSN2023				

# **Book Published**

Sr. no.	Title
01	The Legacy of Vedic Engineering with modern application
02	The Fundamentals of Engineering Mechanics.

# Chapter Published

Sr. no.	Title								
0.1	Abstract	Proceeding	book	of	12th	international	conference	of	'Computing,
01	Communication and Sensor Networks', CCSN2023								

#### Educational Details

Laucational I	Cours			
Exam	Institute	Year	University/Board	Grade
PhD	Babasaheb college of Engineering, Pusad, Yavtmal	2022	SGBU,AMRAVATI	Pursuing (2 <sup>nd</sup> Year)
M. E.	Mahatma Gandhi College of Engineering, Nanded	2014-16	SRTMU, Nanded	First Class
B.E. (Automobile)	Govt. College of Engineering And Research, Awasari, Pune	2009-13	University of Pune	First Class
HSC	Bb Arts Nb Commerce Bp Science College, Digras	2008-09	Maharashtra	Second Class
SSC	Dinbai High School, Digras	2006-07	Maharashtra	First Class

# Experience

#### **Total Teaching Experience: 7 years 4 Months**

Sr. No.	Name of Institute	Year	Post	
1	Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology	30th December 2020 to till date	Assistant Professor	
2	Parvatibai Genba Moze COE ,Wagholi	1 <sup>st</sup> January 2018 to 19 May 2020	Assistant Professor	
3	Babasaheb college of Engineering, Pusad Yavtmal	7 <sup>th</sup> Jul 2016 to April 2017	Assistant Professor	
4	Babasaheb college of Engineering, Pusad Yavtmal	July 2015 to April 2016	Assistant Professor	
5	Government College of Engineering and Research, Awasari, Pune	5 <sup>th</sup> Jan 2015 to 3rd April 2015	Assistant Professor	
Other Experience: 1 Year 7 Months				
1	Tawakkal Auto Garage, Digras, Yavtmal	Jan 2008 to July 2009	Repair and maintenance	

### Paper Published

- 1. Nitin Pawar "Application of LED Bulb with Perforated Plus Shape Fin Array in Mines" journal of Mines metals and fuels,2024
- 2. Nitin Pawar "An Experimental Investigation on Diesel Engine Performance by the Application of Dual Bio-Diesel Blends" journal of Mines metals and fuels,2024
- 3. Nitin Pawar "Performance Analysis on Solar Flat Plate Collector with Reducing Energy Wastage Using Optimal Geometry Application" Journal of Harbin Engineering University, 1380-1387.
- 4. Nitin Namdeo pawar "Design and Evaluation of perforated fins with different aaray of fins structure by an active mode of cooling system" Journal of Mines, Metals and Fuels, 2023
- 5. Nitin Namdeo Pawar, Hameshbabu Nanwala "Study of extrude aluminium alloy led bulb in a passive mode of cooling system with a different array of fin structure" Journal of Material Engineering, Volume 2 Pages 35-43
- 6. Santosh Kumara, Nitin Namdeo Pawara "Design of experiment with tribological performance analysis of electroless nano-composite ni-p-sic coating for conveyors" Tribology in Industry SCI Papers.
- 7. Nitin Namdeo Pawar, Dr. Kiran K Jadhao, Dr. L.S. Bothra, Dr. Santosh Kumar "Design and analysis of pumping housing for water cooled engine system" GIS Science Journal 318-331.
- 8. Nitin Pawar ,"Design and fabrication and testing of a water cooler with a use of heat exchanger as economizer" 7<sup>th</sup> International conference on Innovation and research in Engineering Technology, 8h and 9<sup>th</sup> April 2022 by Elsevier and SSRN 2022.
- 9. Nitin Pawar , Design and fabrication of multi-stage automatic sand separator, 7<sup>th</sup> International conference on Innovation and research in Engineering Technology, 8h and 9<sup>th</sup> April 2022 by Elsevier and SSRN publication
- 10. Mr. Nitin Namdeo Pawar "Design and simulation of a high power led bulbs with different array of fins in passive mode of cooling" Microelectronics, Circuits and Systems, Lecture Notes in Electrical Springer Nature Singapore Pte Ltd. 2023, Engineering 976,
- 11. Mr. Nitin Namdeo Pawar "An experimental investigation of production of plastic fuel and blend with diesel fuel" Microelectronics, Circuits and Systems, Lecture Notes in Electrical Springer Nature Singapore Pte Ltd. 2023, Engineering 976,
- 12. Mr. Nitin N. Pawar "Design, fabrication and testing of a water cooler with a use of heat exchanger as economizer" organized by International Journal of Scientific Research in Engineering and Management during Feb 2022.
- 13. Mr. Nitin N. Pawar "Design and fabrication of multi-stage automatic sand separator" organized by the International Journal of Scientific Research in Engineering and Management during Feb 2022.

- 14. Mr. Nitin N. Pawar "Ozone Generation" organized by the international journal for science and advance research in technology, May 2019
- 15. Mr. Nitin N. Pawar "Cooling of led bulb by using different array of fins" –international journal of innovative research in science and engineering. Volume 2, Issue 07, July 2016.
- 16. Mr. Nitin N. Pawar "Cooling of led bulb by using different array of fins" –5th International Conference on science technology and management on 30th July 2016.
- 17. Mr. Nitin N. Pawar "Cooling of led bulb by using different array of fins" International Conference on research challenges in engineering and technology on 18-19 August 2016
- 18. Mr. Nitin N. Pawar "Analysis of Li-Iron battery performance with respect to temperature and some other parameter" 3rd national conference on research and development in Mechanical, Electronics and Civil Engg.

#### Roles and Responsibilities

- 1. IIC member at Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon, Thane.
- 2. Entrepreneurship Development Cell member at Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon, Thane.
- 3. Event coordinator at Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology , Sapgaon Thane.
- 4. Admission Councillor at Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon Thane.
- 5. NSS PO at Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon Thane
- 6. Coordinator for NAAC in Criteria No. 4. Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon, Thane
- 7. Coordinator for NBA in Criteria No. 8. Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon, Thane
- 8. Physical Director for university Sports at Parvatibai Genba Moze College of Engineering Wagholi, Pune

#### **Subject Taught**

- Engineering Mechanics
- Turbo Machines
- Applied Thermodynamics
- Engineering Graphics
- Alternative fuels
- Automobile

#### Software courses

- Certified course of ANSYS by Indo German Tool Room, Aurangabad.
- Certified course of HYPER MES by Indo German Tool Room, Aurangabad.
- Certified course of FLUENT by Indo German Tool Room, Aurangabad
- Certified course of AUTOCAD by Indo German Tool Room, Aurangabad
- Course of MATLAB.

# Academic Projects:

#### PhD:

**Project Name:** Study of Led Bulbs at Different Parameters for a Passive Mode of the Cooling System

#### **Maser of Engineering:**

**Project Name:** Cooling of LED bulb By Using Different Array of Fins

# **Bachelor of Engineering:**

**Project Name:** Design and Fabrication of Regenerative Braking System.

#### Workshop, Seminar, and Guest Lecture Organized

- 1. Organize a faculty development program on "Internet of Things" for engineering faculties and students in collaboration with Idea Lab, AICTE approved, at Sardar Patel Institute of Engineering in November 2023.
- 2. Organize an industrial visit to DRDO, Pune, for first-year students.

- 3. Organize an industrial visit to GMRT Centre, Narayangaon, Pune, for first-year students.
- 4. Organize an industrial visit to Railway Carshed, Kalyan, for first-year students.
- 5. Organize a faculty development program on "Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality" for engineering faculties using FEAST Software at Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon, Thane, in November 2022.
- 6. Organize an "ENTREPRENEUR DEVELOPMENT PROGRAMME" for engineering students by the Ministry of Skill India, Government of India, at Admission Counselor, Alamuri Ratnamala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon, Thane, in 2022.
- 7. Conduct a national-level seminar on "Social Development of Students" at ARMIET, Sapgoan, Thane.
- 8. Serve as the teacher coordinator for the event "Teachers Day" on September 5, with chief guest Dr. S. B. Singh (Ex-Director of DRDO) at PG Moze COE, Wagholi.
- 9. Serve as the teacher coordinator for the event "Engineers Day" on September 15, with chief guest Dr. D. B. Pedraman (Director, DRDO Lab) at PG Moze COE, Wagholi.
- 10. Arrange a student guidance seminar for MPSC 2019 and GATE 2019 with Chief Guest Mr. Shriram Pawar, CO, Pimpri Chinchwad Municipal, and Mr. Shankar Wadne, GATE Forum Technical Adviser.
- 11. Arrange a one-day workshop on the Assembly and Disassembly of S.I. Engine at BNCOE, Pusad.
- 12. Arrange an industrial visit to the Thermal Power Station, Parali, Beed, Mechanical Engineering students.
- 13. Arrange a one-day visit to Central State Transport Workshop, Nagpur, for TE and BE Mechanical Engineering students

#### Workshop, Seminar and FDPs Attended

Date:

- 1. "Intelligent System for Sustainable Development" organized by St. Peter's Engineering College, Hyderabad, from 8th to 12th June 2021.
- 2. "Introduction to Finite Element Methods for Engineering Applications with ANSYS" organized by G H Raisoni Institute of Business Management, Jalgaon, from 3rd to 8th May 2021.
- 3. "One-week online Faculty Development Program On Emerging Trends in AIML" organized by Alamuri Ratnmala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon, Thane, from 17th to 22nd May 2021.
- 4. "Online short-term training program on Python" organized by Alamuri Ratnmala Institute of Engineering and Technology, Sapgaon, Thane, from 10th to 14th May 2021.
- 5. "How to File a Patent" organized by Alard College of Engineering and Management, Manjari, Pune.
- 6. "Fluid Mechanics and LASER Based Flow Diagnostics" organized by College of Engineering, Pune, & Jost Engineering Company Ltd. Held during 30th & 31st Oct 2018.
- 7. One-day FDP program on "Research Funding and Publications" at PG Moze COE, Wagholi.

vv agnon.				
8. One-day seminar on "Recent Trends in Welding Technology" at JSPM, ICOER, Wagholi				
Personal Details				
DOB:	17 <sup>th</sup> February 1991			
Hobbies:	Trekking, Travelling, Playing Cricket. Reading Novels			
Strengths:	Problem-solving ability, zeal to learn new things, self motivation,			
	Adaptive to any kind of working conditions.			
Permanent Address:	A/P: Shendona, Tal: Manora, Dist: Washim, Maharashtra 444404.			
I hereby declare that the above-written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and				
belief.				
Place:				